that looks good that forehand
come again i know that looking smooth
smooth not so smooth
good how many times do you play this
week two times
one time with the wall only nice you're
still going on the wall
i'm proud of you i like the wall the
wall is fantastic good music
oh you play with music no i don't
recommend
no no you know why i don't recommend
music this is so funny like when i used
to play college tennis
some teams would have music during
practice
and i always hated that and our coach
thankfully never used music
and i would get so distracted when we
would go uh to away matches
and would warm up and they would blast
music here's why i don't like music for
tennis because
tennis is such an intuitive game when
you're listening to music you get
distracted you start thinking about the
music
yes it can be inspirational sometimes
listening to music
but it doesn't really work for tennis in
tennis you really gotta concentrate you
gotta focus
you know that's why everybody has to be
quiet for example
in the stands when players play it's a
sport where you really have to
concentrate and focus
and you don't want noise coming in for
the outside therefore next time do not
use headphones when you're playing on
the wall okay that's right
good better come on
better whoa
what a whipper
better come on oh lala
oh my goodness these are rip shots
whoa
better it's better on a beautiful
forehand
maybe the best forehand of your life but
nick i have a question about
like directions go ahead when the ball
is going across the court sometimes i
feel like
the opponent is standing and we are
rallying and i want it
to be easy for the partner yeah so when
i do it
the ball is not going the way i want
all the time and especially if he is
like
when she is outside of that corner okay
i got you i mean does it mean i have to
turn my body a little bit
more away so the sense so i finished not
in the middle okay that's a really
really good question so you know
like right now at this stage of your
game when you're playing with other
people
are you rallying like mostly through the
middle yeah
okay but i want to be able to like when
the person went this way i wanted to be
easy for him and return the ball
to the close proximity where he right so
here's the deal with uh directional
control if you rally with someone
through the middle and you're
hitting it right to that person you
actually are working on directional
control
so it's not so easy to get the ball
right down the center every time
so if you master that skill if you can
hit the ball right down the center
that means that you can hit it anywhere
on the court that's number one
okay so don't worry that you're rallying
uh through the middle of the court
you are working on directional control
by doing that
now you notice how sometimes when we
rally when we do drills
i will stand in the corners and i'll
have you hit to me so i did that very
early on i was very sneaky
about that this was maybe our third or
fourth session i would already start
sneaking i didn't tell you anything
right i would just slide to the corner
and you would start hitting to me
and that's where you learned how to
let's say aim
because here's the problem with aiming
if you are literally aiming with the
racket towards the target
you're doing yourself a big disservice
because you're slowing down
at the moment of contact and you are
steering the ball pushing it guiding it
towards the target and what you want to
do instead
is make a small change in the angle of
the racket face at the moment of contact
so
the fascinating thing about tennis is
that this angle of the racket face
change is so miniscule that you do this
movement intuitively
and you already know how to do it you're
not aware that you know how to do it but
you already know how to aim
intuitively and we'll learn that very
early on i'm going to prove it to you
right now
okay and i'm going to prove to you now
that you already know how to aim so
these i want you to hit right through
the middle of the chord
down the center here we go
very nice very nice
okay now go to the left which is
basically cross court i want you to hit
your forehand to the left
okay good
another one okay now hit your forehand
to the right
which is inside out you're gonna hit the
forehand to the right
here we go good
okay it's okay if you miss i'm gonna hit
it to the right
all right now how did you do that you
have no idea right
you're brilliant you are brilliant for
sure you are brilliant
but you have no idea in other words
there was no conscious changing
in the angle of the racket face of
contact you didn't think of anything you
just hit the ball
i told you where to go and you just went
there i feel like you tricked me
i didn't try no i have no idea how i did
it well like i told you the way
directional control works
is the racket angle of the racket face
of contact so if i hold my racket
like this if it's like let's say aligned
with the baseline like this
it's completely parallel to the baseline
if you hit that ball it's going to go
right down the middle now we're assuming
that we're going to have the same finish
on all strokes
okay if we turn the racket just slightly
over this way look just a slight
angle change now that ball is going to
go cross-court because over the length
of the court the angle doesn't have to
be that big
yeah so we're talking about a small
little change so the important thing
is your question when you ask me how do
i aim
is just to tell yourself where you're
going to go and do not do what most rec
players do
is by literally aiming let me show you
so most players will
aim by going towards the target with the
with the racket so when they go
cross-court it will go cross-court with
the racquet
down the middle that will go down the
middle with the racket and inside out
they will go
towards the target with the racket so
they're literally steering the ball
towards the target now what that is it's
an inferior forehand because you're
losing a lot of acceleration you're
slowing down
the moment of contact and you're losing
a lot of speed because of that so you
should do instead
is what you just demonstrated here is by
simply telling yourself
i'm gonna hit the forehand down the
middle cross-court inside out and just
do it
because you already know how to do it
and don't change a single thing
ana so are you more clear now on how to
aim in tennis yeah you're not gonna
you're not concerned about it anymore no
you don't be concerned
just trust in your guts trust in your
guts you already know how to do it and
your concern
initially was like hitting it right to
the person sometimes
you might not be able to hit it to them
because of other technical flaws it's
not the fact that you can't aim
maybe you're hitting the ball late your
timing is off maybe you're you're doing
a mishit you're moving your wrist that
contact could be many different things
but you should definitely not concern
yourself with trying to aim and spend
any thoughts
about that at all okay i decided i just
want to hit inside of the court and let
them run around yeah and there's
absolutely nothing
more good well listen there's absolutely
nothing wrong with
hitting right to the person down the
middle like i said this is going to
train you to
direct the balls to other parts of the
court as well the middle is my bread and
butter anyways
there's nothing wrong with the middle
yeah do you know how the pros warm up
have you ever been to a tournament
yes professional tournament where in del
rey right yes if you see how the one off
they're going up down the middle
yeah yeah and one thing you can do which
is good is like you go
half court so you can go from like from
here to here so have
your partner stand over there on that
side and you guys rally cross court
there's something you can do you know as
an addition to that okay and i'm going
to test you now see if you
know how to aim with the incoming ball
go cross-court
okay cross-court again
cross-court again get a little more
angle on it
all right now go down the line
down the line again
all right hit it cross-court you got a
little to jam there cross court again
and match point your choice you call it
where you going
cross court
absolutely perfect it's okay listen when
i was
giving you a little bit of pressure
there that's why your forehead was a
little bit tight that's normal
but uh see how easy aiming is you
already know how to do it
therefore don't worry about it good job